

Simon Griffee

Designer & Photographer

Base: New York City **Phone:** +1 (347) 498-5369

Email & Facetime: simon@hypertexthero.com
Design Portfolio: hypertexthero.com/work
Photo Portfolio: simongriffee.com/stories

Summary

Over a decade of professional experience with visual and web design while travelling extensively around the world and living in Brazil, Tunisia, Italy, England and the United States.

I speak and write in **English** and **Portuguese** fluently, in **Italian** well, and in **French** and **Spanish** in a somewhat amusing way. Using these together with **visual and programming languages** I have managed to:

- Raise funding for international organizations by completing branding and user experience design projects in digital and print media.
- · Save companies time and money with good websites and thoughtful design.
- Help groups and individuals with hands-on design, coding, editing, brainstorming and wine tasting.

I enjoy learning and absorbing information from different fields.

Experience

Information Systems Officer, International Plant Protection Convention

Food and Agriculture Organization, United Nations, Rome, Italy, June 2009–Present: Helped increase funding from donors, increase number of contracting parties to the convention and increase the general public's awareness of the International Plant Protection Convention's (IPPC) work while making people using computers there happier. Provided design support and technical advice on the creation and evolution of websites and other digital media as well as hands-on design and coding work at all stages. Organized photo groups and food and wine tasting on Fridays.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer · Hypertexthero, Worldwide, 2005–Present: Completed a variety of web and print projects for clients around the world, from large companies in London and internet start-ups in the Bay Area to non-profits and United Nations agencies in Rome.

Web & Graphic Designer · *Acotel Group S.p.A, Rome, Italy, 2003–2004:*Created the first web standards based website design project in Italy.
Completed identity design projects and marketing and advertising multimedia campaigns.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer

European Artisans, Various, Rome, Italy, 1999–2003: Freelance designer for an internet startup and various clients.

Education

I learned to work with computers with computer games. I learned graphic design from books, posters and films by some of my favorite designers like Milton Glaser, Saul Bass and Paul Rand. I learned HTML and CSS by viewing the source of websites I liked, searching with Google and with Jeffrey Zeldman's Designing With Web Standards. I learned user experience, usability and accessibility principles from a book called The Cluetrain Manifesto and from Jacob Nielsen's Alertbox column. I learned photography by taking and looking at photographs. I learned photography by taking and looking at photographs. I learned to cook and to eat in Italy. I've been learning some Python and enjoyed meeting Alex Martelli in Florence in 2013. My traditional education occurred at:

Magnum Photos, 2011, 2012 and 2013 Workshops
Stanford University, 2006 · Concept Design Workshop at Stanford University's d.school
Bournemouth University, 1996–1999 · B.A. with Honours in Creative Advertising
Bournemouth & Poole College of Art & Design, 1997–1998
City & Guilds Diploma with Distinction in Photography

Skills, Tools & Interests

Web development: I like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, web standards and open source software. If a tool is the right one for the job I'll use it.

User experience design, usability, accessibility: I like fast, simple interfaces and good writing over excessive style.

Photography: I work with Leica rangefinder cameras and Fuji and Ricoh compacts. I want a better, more affordable camera for photography students and better editing software.

Software: I spend most of my time in Photoshop, Sketch, Illustrator, Lightroom, InDesign and in Textmate and a Terminal prompt. I also have some experience with Python and Django, PHP, Wordpress, Drupal and Textpattern, Ruby and Jekyll, Git and Github, Apache and Nginx, a little MySQL and PostgreSQL and a bit of Unix system administration.

Interests: Communication, information, photography, web, travel, open source & open internet, philosophy, typography, art history, nature, astronomy, computer simulations, music, (blues guitar, jazz, classical), vintage aeroplanes, basketball.